{
    "quizId": "111111",
    "quizTitle": "MyQuiz",
    "quizDomain": {
        "domainId": 112,
        "domain": "CPP"
    },
    "quizDuration": "1",
    "questions": [
        {
            "questionId": "91",
            "question": "To get polymorphism for a class you have to mark your methods as",
            "difficulty": "EASY",
            "correctOption": "Virtual",
            "domain": {
                "domainId": 112,
                "domain": "CPP"
            },
            "option1": "Static",
            "option2": "Pure virtual",
            "option3": "Virtual",
            "option4": "Final"
        },
        {
            "questionId": "92",
            "question": "Where does memory get allocated for a static data members of a class",
            "difficulty": "EASY",
            "correctOption": "Data",
            "domain": {
                "domainId": 112,
                "domain": "CPP"
            },
            "option1": "Code/text",
            "option2": "Stack",
            "option3": "Heap",
            "option4": "Data"
        },
        {
            "questionId": "93",
            "question": "The default access scope for a method in a C++ class is",
            "difficulty": "EASY",
            "correctOption": "Private",
            "domain": {
                "domainId": 112,
                "domain": "CPP"
            },
            "option1": "Private",
            "option2": "Public",
            "option3": "Protected",
            "option4": "Default"
        },
        {
            "questionId": "94",
            "question": "The operator used for getting the type_info object is",
            "difficulty": "EASY",
            "correctOption": "Typeid",
            "domain": {
                "domainId": 112,
                "domain": "CPP"
            },
            "option1": "Typeof",
            "option2": "Typeid",
            "option3": "Type",
            "option4": "Typeinfo"
        },
        {
            "questionId": "95",
            "question": "Which of the following is the base class of C++ steam class hierarchy?",
            "difficulty": "EASY",
            "correctOption": "ios",
            "domain": {
                "domainId": 112,
                "domain": "CPP"
            },
            "option1": "istream",
            "option2": "iostream",
            "option3": "stream",
            "option4": "ios"
        },
        {
            "questionId": "96",
            "question": "class Foo {  int i; }; In the above sample, what is the member access specifier of the member data i ?",
            "difficulty": "EASY",
            "correctOption": "private",
            "domain": {
                "domainId": 112,
                "domain": "CPP"
            },
            "option1": "default",
            "option2": "virtual",
            "option3": "private",
            "option4": "protected"
        },
        {
            "questionId": "97",
            "question": "Which of the following is the default namespace of C++?",
            "difficulty": "EASY",
            "correctOption": "stdio",
            "domain": {
                "domainId": 112,
                "domain": "CPP"
            },
            "option1": "iostream",
            "option2": "standard",
            "option3": "std",
            "option4": "stdio"
        },
        {
            "questionId": "98",
            "question": "what happens to the automatic objects that have been constructed in a try block when that block throws an exception ?",
            "difficulty": "EASY",
            "correctOption": "Destructors are called for each of the objects",
            "domain": {
                "domainId": 112,
                "domain": "CPP"
            },
            "option1": "only throws exception",
            "option2": "Destructors are called for each of the objects",
            "option3": "same as for other variables.",
            "option4": "None of the above."
        },
        {
            "questionId": "99",
            "question": " In C++ programs the operation of the assignment operator and that of the copy constructor are",
            "difficulty": "EASY",
            "correctOption": "similar except that the copy constructor creates a new object",
            "domain": {
                "domainId": 112,
                "domain": "CPP"
            },
            "option1": "similar except that the copy constructor creates a new object",
            "option2": "different except that they both copy member data.",
            "option3": "both  (1)  and (2)",
            "option4": "None of the above."
        },
        {
            "questionId": "100",
            "question": "when two or more objects are derived from a common base class, u can prevent multiple copies of the base                           class from being present in an object derived from those objects by declaring base class when it is                           inherited.",
            "difficulty": "EASY",
            "correctOption": "Virtual",
            "domain": {
                "domainId": 112,
                "domain": "CPP"
            },
            "option1": "public",
            "option2": "Protected",
            "option3": "Virtual",
            "option4": "Private"
        },
        {
            "questionId": "101",
            "question": "which one support unknown data types in a single framework ?",
            "difficulty": "EASY",
            "correctOption": "templates",
            "domain": {
                "domainId": 112,
                "domain": "CPP"
            },
            "option1": "inheritance",
            "option2": "virtual functions",
            "option3": "abstract base class",
            "option4": "templates"
        },
        {
            "questionId": "102",
            "question": "Which of the following is the correct syntax to print the message in C++ language?",
            "difficulty": "EASY",
            "correctOption": "cout <<'Hello world!';",
            "domain": {
                "domainId": 112,
                "domain": "CPP"
            },
            "option1": "cout <<'Hello world!';",
            "option2": "Cout << Hello world! ;",
            "option3": "Out <<Hello world!;",
            "option4": "None of the above"
        },
        {
            "questionId": "103",
            "question": "Which of the following is the correct identifier?",
            "difficulty": "EASY",
            "correctOption": "VAR_123",
            "domain": {
                "domainId": 112,
                "domain": "CPP"
            },
            "option1": "$var_name",
            "option2": "VAR_123",
            "option3": "varname@",
            "option4": "None of the above"
        },
        {
            "questionId": "104",
            "question": "Which of the following is the address operator?",
            "difficulty": "EASY",
            "correctOption": "&",
            "domain": {
                "domainId": 112,
                "domain": "CPP"
            },
            "option1": "@",
            "option2": "#",
            "option3": "&",
            "option4": "%"
        },
        {
            "questionId": "105",
            "question": "Which of the following features must be supported by any programming language to become a pure object-oriented programming language?",
            "difficulty": "EASY",
            "correctOption": "All of the above",
            "domain": {
                "domainId": 112,
                "domain": "CPP"
            },
            "option1": "Encapsulation",
            "option2": "Inheritance",
            "option3": "Polymorphism",
            "option4": "All of the above"
        },
        {
            "questionId": "106",
            "question": "The programming language that has the ability to create new data types is called___.",
            "difficulty": "EASY",
            "correctOption": "Extensible",
            "domain": {
                "domainId": 112,
                "domain": "CPP"
            },
            "option1": "Overloaded",
            "option2": "Encapsulated",
            "option3": "Reprehensible",
            "option4": "Extensible"
        },
        {
            "questionId": "107",
            "question": "Which of the following is the original creator of the C++ language?",
            "difficulty": "EASY",
            "correctOption": "Bjarne Stroustrup",
            "domain": {
                "domainId": 112,
                "domain": "CPP"
            },
            "option1": "Dennis Ritchie",
            "option2": "Ken Thompson",
            "option3": "Bjarne Stroustrup",
            "option4": "Brian Kernighan"
        },
        {
            "questionId": "108",
            "question": "Which of the following statements is correct about the formal parameters in C++?",
            "difficulty": "EASY",
            "correctOption": "Parameters with which functions are called",
            "domain": {
                "domainId": 112,
                "domain": "CPP"
            },
            "option1": "Parameters with which functions are called",
            "option2": "Parameters which are used in the definition of the function",
            "option3": "Variables other than passed parameters in a function",
            "option4": "Variables that are never used in the function"
        },
        {
            "questionId": "109",
            "question": "Which of the following is the correct syntax to read the single character to console in the C++ language?",
            "difficulty": "EASY",
            "correctOption": "get(ch)",
            "domain": {
                "domainId": 112,
                "domain": "CPP"
            },
            "option1": "Read ch()",
            "option2": "Getline vh()",
            "option3": "get(ch)",
            "option4": "Scanf(ch)"
        },
        {
            "questionId": "110",
            "question": "The C++ language is ______ object-oriented language.",
            "difficulty": "EASY",
            "correctOption": "Semi Object-oriented or Partial Object-oriented",
            "domain": {
                "domainId": 112,
                "domain": "CPP"
            },
            "option1": "Pure Object oriented",
            "option2": "Not Object oriented",
            "option3": "Semi Object-oriented or Partial Object-oriented",
            "option4": "None of the above"
        },
        {
            "questionId": "111",
            "question": "Which of the following comment syntax is correct to create a single-line comment in the C++ program?",
            "difficulty": "EASY",
            "correctOption": "//Comment",
            "domain": {
                "domainId": 112,
                "domain": "CPP"
            },
            "option1": "//Comment",
            "option2": "/ Comment",
            "option3": "Comment//",
            "option4": "None of the above"
        },
       
        {
            "questionId": "113",
            "question": "Which of the following refers to characteristics of an array?",
            "difficulty": "EASY",
            "correctOption": "An array is a set of similar data items",
            "domain": {
                "domainId": 112,
                "domain": "CPP"
            },
            "option1": "An array is a set of similar data items",
            "option2": "An array is a set of distinct data items",
            "option3": "An array can hold different types of datatypes",
            "option4": "None of the above"
        },
      
        {
            "questionId": "115",
            "question": "If we stored five elements or data items in an array, what will be the index address or the index number of the array's last data item?",
            "difficulty": "EASY",
            "correctOption": "4",
            "domain": {
                "domainId": 112,
                "domain": "CPP"
            },
            "option1": "3",
            "option2": "5",
            "option3": "4",
            "option4": "88"
        },
        {
            "questionId": "116",
            "question": "If we stored five elements or data items in an array, what will be the index address or the index number of the array's last data item?",
            "difficulty": "EASY",
            "correctOption": "Sorting is a type of process in which the data or information is ordered into a specific order. Example  increasing orders, decreasing.",
            "domain": {
                "domainId": 112,
                "domain": "CPP"
            },
            "option1": "Sorting is a type of process in which the data or information is ordered into a specific order. Example  increasing orders, decreasing.",
            "option2": "Sorting information or data only in increasing order",
            "option3": "Sorting is a type of process in which data elements are modified or manipulated",
            "option4": "None of the above"
        },
        {
            "questionId": "117",
            "question": "How many types of the array are there in the C++ programming language?",
            "difficulty": "EASY",
            "correctOption": "In the C++ programming language, there are two types of arrays",
            "domain": {
                "domainId": 112,
                "domain": "CPP"
            },
            "option1": "In the C++ programming language, there are three types of arrays",
            "option2": "In the C++ programming language, there are four types of arrays",
            "option3": "In the C++ programming language, there are two types of arrays",
            "option4": "Both 1 and 2"
        },
        {
            "questionId": "118",
            "question": "In C++, for what purpose the rank() is used?",
            "difficulty": "EASY",
            "correctOption": "It returns the dimension of the specified array",
            "domain": {
                "domainId": 112,
                "domain": "CPP"
            },
            "option1": "It returns the size of each dimension",
            "option2": "It returns the maximum number of elements that can be stored in the array",
            "option3": "It returns the dimension of the specified array",
            "option4": "None of the above"
        },
        {
            "questionId": "119",
            "question": " Which of the following can be considered as the object of an array?",
            "difficulty": "EASY",
            "correctOption": "Elements of the Array",
            "domain": {
                "domainId": 112,
                "domain": "CPP"
            },
            "option1": "Elements of the Array",
            "option2": "Functions of the Array",
            "option3": "Index of an array",
            "option4": "All of the above"
        }
       
    ]
}